<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2 | Li Group</title>
    <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication_types/2/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication_types/2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>2</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://wlibuaa.github.io/images/logo_huf78e711280e2ffb29500bba5b0998b63_67904_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication_types/2/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symmetry-Protected Topological Edge Modes and Emergent Partial Time-Reversal Symmetry Breaking in Open Quantum Many-Body Systems</title>
      <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/li-2021-prl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/li-2021-prl/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Many-Body Simulations of the Two-Dimensional Fermi-Hubbard Model in Ultracold Optical Lattices</title>
      <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/chen-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/chen-2021/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evidence of the Berezinskii-Kosterlitz-Thouless phase in a frustrated magnet</title>
      <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/li-2020-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/li-2020-c/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universal thermodynamics in the Kitaev fractional liquid</title>
      <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/li-2020-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/li-2020-b/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Differentiation for Second Renormalization of Tensor Networks</title>
      <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/chen-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/chen-2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kosterlitz-Thouless melting of magnetic order in the triangular quantum Ising material TmMgGaO$_4$</title>
      <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/li-2020-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/li-2020-a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TmMgGaO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; is one of a number of recently-synthesized quantum magnets that are proposed to realize important theoretical models. Here the authors demonstrate the agreement between detailed experimental measurements and state-of-the-art predictions based on the 2D transverse field triangular lattice Ising model.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thermal Tensor Network Simulations of the Heisenberg Model on the Bethe Lattice</title>
      <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/qu-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/qu-2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thermal Tensor Renormalization Group Simulations of Square-Lattice Quantum Spin Models</title>
      <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/li-2019-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/li-2019-c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this work, we benchmark the well-controlled and numerically accurate exponential thermal tensor renormalization group (XTRG) in the simulation of interacting spin models in two dimensions. Finite temperature introduces a finite thermal correlation length $\xi$, such that for system sizes $L \gg \xi$ finite-size calculations actually simulate the thermodynamic limit. In this paper, we focus on the square lattice Heisenberg antiferromagnet (SLH) and quantum Ising models (QIM) on open and cylindrical geometries up to width W=10. We explore various one-dimensional mapping paths in the matrix product operator (MPO) representation, whose performance is clearly shown to be geometry dependent. We benchmark against quantum Monte Carlo (QMC) data, yet also the series-expansion thermal tensor network results. Thermal properties including the internal energy, specific heat, and spin structure factors, etc. are computed with high precision, obtaining excellent agreement with QMC results. XTRG also allows us to reach remarkably low temperatures. For SLH, we obtain an energy per site $u_g^&lt;em&gt;$≃−0.6694(4) and a spontaneous magnetization $m_S^&lt;/em&gt;\simeq$0.30(1) already consistent with the ground-state properties, which is obtained from extrapolated low-T thermal data on W≤8 cylinders and W≤10 open strips, respectively. We extract an exponential divergence versus T of the structure factor S(M), as well as the correlation length ξ, at the ordering wave vector M=(π,π), which represents the renormalized classical behavior and can be observed over a narrow but appreciable temperature window, by analyzing the finite-size data by XTRG simulations. For the QIM with a finite-temperature phase transition, we employ several thermal quantities, including the specific heat, Binder ratio, as well as the MPO entanglement to determine the critical temperature $T_c$.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two-Temperature Scales in the Triangular-Lattice Heisenberg Antiferromagnet</title>
      <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/chen-2019-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/chen-2019-a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The anomalous thermodynamic properties of the paradigmatic frustrated spin-1/2 triangular-lattice Heisenberg antiferromagnet (TLH) has remained an open topic of research over decades, both experimentally and theoretically. Here, we further the theoretical understanding based on the recently developed, powerful exponential tensor renormalization group method on cylinders and stripes in a quasi-one-dimensional (1D) setup, as well as a tensor product operator approach directly in 2D. The observed thermal properties of the TLH are in excellent agreement with two recent experimental measurements on the virtually ideal TLH material Ba8CoNb6O24. Remarkably, our numerical simulations reveal two crossover temperature scales, at Tl/J$∼$0.20 and Th/J$∼$0.55, with J the Heisenberg exchange coupling, which are also confirmed by a more careful inspection of the experimental data. We propose that in the intermediate regime between the low-temperature scale Tl and the higher one Th, the ``rotonlike&#39;&#39; excitations are activated with a strong chiral component and a large contribution to thermal entropies. Bearing remarkable resemblance to the renowned roton thermodynamics in liquid helium, these gapped excitations suppress the incipient 120$∘$ order that emerges for temperatures below Tl.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nontopological Majorana Zero Modes in Inhomogeneous Spin Ladders</title>
      <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/robinson-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/robinson-2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exponential Thermal Tensor Network Approach for Quantum Lattice Models</title>
      <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/chen-2018-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/chen-2018-c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We speed up thermal simulations of quantum many-body systems in both one- (1D) and two-dimensional (2D) models in an exponential way by iteratively projecting the thermal density matrix $\rho=e^{-\beta H}$ onto itself. We refer to this scheme of doubling $\beta$ in each step of the imaginary time evolution as the exponential tensor renormalization group (XTRG). This approach is in stark contrast to conventional Trotter-Suzuki-type methods which evolve $\rho$ on a linear quasicontinuous grid in inverse temperature $\beta\equiv1/T$. As an aside, the large steps in XTRG allow one to swiftly jump across finite-temperature phase transitions, i.e., without the need to resolve each singularly expensive phase-transition point right away, e.g., when interested in low-energy behavior. A fine temperature resolution can be obtained, nevertheless, by using interleaved temperature grids. In general, XTRG can reach low temperatures exponentially fast and, thus, not only saves computational time but also merits better accuracy due to significantly fewer truncation steps. For similar reasons, we also find that the series expansion thermal tensor network approach benefits in both efficiency and precision, from the logarithmic temperature scale setup. We work in an (effective) 1D setting exploiting matrix product operators (MPOs), which allows us to fully and uniquely implement non-Abelian and Abelian symmetries to greatly enhance numerical performance. We use our XTRG machinery to explore the thermal properties of Heisenberg models on 1D chains and 2D square and triangular lattices down to low temperatures approaching ground-state properties. The entanglement properties, as well as the renormalization-group flow of entanglement spectra in MPOs, are discussed, where logarithmic entropies (approximately $\ln{\beta}$) are shown in both spin chains and square-lattice models with gapless towers of states. We also reveal that XTRG can be employed to accurately simulate the Heisenberg XXZ model on the square lattice which undergoes a thermal phase transition. We determine its critical temperature based on thermal physical observables, as well as entanglement measures. Overall, we demonstrate that XTRG provides an elegant, versatile, and highly competitive approach to explore thermal properties, including finite-temperature thermal phase transitions as well as the different ordering tendencies at various temperature scales for frustrated systems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topological and Geometric Universal Thermodynamics in Conformal Field Theory</title>
      <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/wang-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/wang-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conformal Thermal Tensor Network and Universal Entropy on Topological Manifolds</title>
      <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/chen-2017-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/chen-2017-c/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universal Boundary Entropies in Conformal Field Theory: A Quantum Monte Carlo Study</title>
      <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/tang-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/tang-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bilayer Linearized Tensor Renormalization Group Approach for Thermal Tensor Networks</title>
      <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/dong-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/dong-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Series-Expansion Thermal Tensor Network Approach for Quantum Lattice Models</title>
      <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/chen-2017-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/chen-2017-b/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Criticality-Enhanced Magnetocaloric Effect in Quantum Spin Chain Material Copper Nitrate</title>
      <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/xiang-2017-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/xiang-2017-a/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hexagon-Singlet Solid Ansatz for the Spin-1 Kagome Antiferromagnet</title>
      <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/li-2015-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/li-2015-a/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topology-Driven Phase Transitions in the Classical Monomer-Dimer-Loop Model</title>
      <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/li-2015-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/li-2015-c/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Criticality in Translation-Invariant Parafermion Chains</title>
      <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/li-2015-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/li-2015-b/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplex Valence-Bond Crystal in the Spin-1 Kagome Heisenberg Antiferromagnet</title>
      <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/liu-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/liu-2015/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kosterlitz-Thouless Transitions and Phase Diagrams of the Interacting Monomer-Dimer Model on a Checkerboard Lattice</title>
      <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/li-2014-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/li-2014-a/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topology and Criticality in the Resonating Affleck-Kennedy-Lieb-Tasaki Loop Spin Liquid States</title>
      <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/li-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/li-2014/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identifying Symmetry-Protected Topological Order by Entanglement Entropy</title>
      <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/li-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/li-2013/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Simulation of Infinite Tree Tensor Network States on the Bethe Lattice</title>
      <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/li-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/li-2012/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matrix Product State and Quantum Phase Transitions in the One-Dimensional Extended Quantum Compass Model</title>
      <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/liu-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/liu-2012/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linearized Tensor Renormalization Group Algorithm for the Calculation of Thermodynamic Properties of Quantum Lattice Models</title>
      <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/li-2011-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/li-2011-a/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phase Transitions and Thermodynamics of the Two-Dimensional Ising Model on a Distorted Kagome Lattice</title>
      <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/li-2010-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/li-2010-a/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Phase Transition, $O(3)$ Universality Class, and Phase Diagram of the Spin-$frac12$ Heisenberg Antiferromagnet on a Distorted Honeycomb Lattice: A Tensor Renormalization-Group Study</title>
      <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/li-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/li-2010/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
