<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ziyu Chen | Li Group</title>
    <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/authors/ziyu-chen/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://wlibuaa.github.io/authors/ziyu-chen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Ziyu Chen</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://wlibuaa.github.io/images/logo_huf78e711280e2ffb29500bba5b0998b63_67904_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url>
      <title>Ziyu Chen</title>
      <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/authors/ziyu-chen/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thermal Tensor Renormalization Group Simulations of Square-Lattice Quantum Spin Models</title>
      <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/li-2019-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/li-2019-c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this work, we benchmark the well-controlled and numerically accurate exponential thermal tensor renormalization group (XTRG) in the simulation of interacting spin models in two dimensions. Finite temperature introduces a finite thermal correlation length $\xi$, such that for system sizes $L \gg \xi$ finite-size calculations actually simulate the thermodynamic limit. In this paper, we focus on the square lattice Heisenberg antiferromagnet (SLH) and quantum Ising models (QIM) on open and cylindrical geometries up to width W=10. We explore various one-dimensional mapping paths in the matrix product operator (MPO) representation, whose performance is clearly shown to be geometry dependent. We benchmark against quantum Monte Carlo (QMC) data, yet also the series-expansion thermal tensor network results. Thermal properties including the internal energy, specific heat, and spin structure factors, etc. are computed with high precision, obtaining excellent agreement with QMC results. XTRG also allows us to reach remarkably low temperatures. For SLH, we obtain an energy per site $u_g^&lt;em&gt;$≃−0.6694(4) and a spontaneous magnetization $m_S^&lt;/em&gt;\simeq$0.30(1) already consistent with the ground-state properties, which is obtained from extrapolated low-T thermal data on W≤8 cylinders and W≤10 open strips, respectively. We extract an exponential divergence versus T of the structure factor S(M), as well as the correlation length ξ, at the ordering wave vector M=(π,π), which represents the renormalized classical behavior and can be observed over a narrow but appreciable temperature window, by analyzing the finite-size data by XTRG simulations. For the QIM with a finite-temperature phase transition, we employ several thermal quantities, including the specific heat, Binder ratio, as well as the MPO entanglement to determine the critical temperature $T_c$.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exponential Thermal Tensor Network Approach for Quantum Lattice Models</title>
      <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/chen-2018-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/chen-2018-c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We speed up thermal simulations of quantum many-body systems in both one- (1D) and two-dimensional (2D) models in an exponential way by iteratively projecting the thermal density matrix $\rho=e^{-\beta H}$ onto itself. We refer to this scheme of doubling $\beta$ in each step of the imaginary time evolution as the exponential tensor renormalization group (XTRG). This approach is in stark contrast to conventional Trotter-Suzuki-type methods which evolve $\rho$ on a linear quasicontinuous grid in inverse temperature $\beta\equiv1/T$. As an aside, the large steps in XTRG allow one to swiftly jump across finite-temperature phase transitions, i.e., without the need to resolve each singularly expensive phase-transition point right away, e.g., when interested in low-energy behavior. A fine temperature resolution can be obtained, nevertheless, by using interleaved temperature grids. In general, XTRG can reach low temperatures exponentially fast and, thus, not only saves computational time but also merits better accuracy due to significantly fewer truncation steps. For similar reasons, we also find that the series expansion thermal tensor network approach benefits in both efficiency and precision, from the logarithmic temperature scale setup. We work in an (effective) 1D setting exploiting matrix product operators (MPOs), which allows us to fully and uniquely implement non-Abelian and Abelian symmetries to greatly enhance numerical performance. We use our XTRG machinery to explore the thermal properties of Heisenberg models on 1D chains and 2D square and triangular lattices down to low temperatures approaching ground-state properties. The entanglement properties, as well as the renormalization-group flow of entanglement spectra in MPOs, are discussed, where logarithmic entropies (approximately $\ln{\beta}$) are shown in both spin chains and square-lattice models with gapless towers of states. We also reveal that XTRG can be employed to accurately simulate the Heisenberg XXZ model on the square lattice which undergoes a thermal phase transition. We determine its critical temperature based on thermal physical observables, as well as entanglement measures. Overall, we demonstrate that XTRG provides an elegant, versatile, and highly competitive approach to explore thermal properties, including finite-temperature thermal phase transitions as well as the different ordering tendencies at various temperature scales for frustrated systems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Series-Expansion Thermal Tensor Network Approach for Quantum Lattice Models</title>
      <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/chen-2017-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/chen-2017-b/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topology-Driven Phase Transitions in the Classical Monomer-Dimer-Loop Model</title>
      <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/li-2015-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/li-2015-c/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kosterlitz-Thouless Transitions and Phase Diagrams of the Interacting Monomer-Dimer Model on a Checkerboard Lattice</title>
      <link>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/li-2014-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wlibuaa.github.io/publication/li-2014-a/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
